# Dripto M. Debroy | Curriculum Vitae

Durham, NC

☑ dripto@phy.duke.edu • ② dripto.github.io

I am a Physics PhD student in the Brown Lab at Duke University with a focus on quantum error correction. My research is focused on schemes for near term error mitigation and correction, along with development of physically inspired error models for ion trap quantum computers.

## **Education**

Duke University Durham, NC

PhD in Physics, Anticipated graduation in May 2021

Advisor: Dr. Kenneth R. Brown

Advisor: Dr. Kenneth R. Brown

UC Santa Barbara, College of Creative Studies

Bachelor of Science in Physics, High Honors

**Santa Barbara, CA** *2012–2016* 

August 2016-Present

# **Research Experience**

#### PhD Candidate

Duke University

Department of Physics – Brown Lab

January 2018 - Present

Working on quantum error correction with a focus on near term error models. As an ion trap group we mostly consider error models seen in our labs. Additional work on qubit mapping problems for scalable ion-trap quantum computers and optimal circuit compiling for error resilience.

#### **Undergraduate Research Assistant**

UC Santa Barbara

Department of Physics – Peng Oh Group

October 2015 - February 2016

Simulated the attenuation of Lyman- $\alpha$  line photons through ionization regions simulated by external collaborators. Seeked anti-correlation between Ly- $\alpha$  regions and 21cm regions in order to better understand real world interferometry data.

#### **Undergraduate Research Assistant**

UC Santa Barbara

Department of Physics - Lubin Lab

May 2014 - September 2014

Worked on the Morphable Mirror Telescope (MMT) project. Was in charge of developing the control code for a large system consisting of a FARO laser tracker, multiple actuators, and positional sensors. Code was able to autonomously regulate curvature of mirror without the need for heavy reinforcement.

#### **Honors**

## Charles Townes/Perkin-Elmer Fellow

**Duke University** 

Duke University Physics Department

Fall 2020

The Charles Townes/Perkin-Elmer Fellowship was created in 1981 by Prof. Charles Townes and the Perkin-Elmer corporation to recognize "an outstanding Duke physics graduate student."

#### **QISE-NET Fellow**

**Duke University/Google AI Quantum** 

National Science Foundation

Feb 2020 - Present

QISE-NET is a fellowship where a graduate student, their academic advisor, and an industry/national lab collaborator form a triplet which receives funding for the student to meet with their industry/national lab collaborator and work on problems of mutual interest. My triplet is myself, my advisor Prof. Kenneth R. Brown, and Dr. Jarrod McClean of Google AI Quantum, and our project is on adapting flag qubit schemes for near term error detection.

#### Summer Undergraduate Research Fellow

**UC Santa Barbara** 

UCSB College of Creative Studies

Summer 2014

Recieved a stipend to support summer research with the lab of Dr. Phil Lubin. The fellowship was provided by the College of Creative Studies at UC Santa Barbara, and was over a two month period. After the conclusion of the fellowship the resulting research was presented at a poster session during UCSB Science Week.

## **Publications**

- TILT: Achieving Higher Fidelity on a Trapped-Ion Linear-Tape Quantum Computing Architecture X-C Wu, DM Debroy, Y Ding, J Baker, Y Alexeev, KR Brown, F Chong arXiv preprint, 2010.15876, to appear in HPCA '21
- Fault-Tolerant Operation of a Quantum Error-Correction Code.
   L Egan, DM Debroy, C Noel, A Risinger, D Zhu, D Biswas, M Newman, M Li, KR Brown, M Cetina, C Monroe arXiv preprint, 2009.11482
- Extended Flag Gadgets for Low-Overhead Circuit Verification.
   DM Debroy, KR Brown
   Physical Review A, 102, 052409 (2020).
- Architecting Noisy Intermediate-Scale Trapped Ion Quantum Computers.
   P Murali, DM Debroy, KR Brown, M Martonosi
   International Symposium on Computer Architecture, ISCA20, 529 542 (2020).
- Logical Performance of 9 Qubit Compass Codes in Ion Traps with Crosstalk Errors.
   DM Debroy, M Li, S Huang, KR Brown
   Quantum Science and Technology, 5, 034002 (2020).
- Stabilizer Slicing: Coherent Error Cancellations in Low-Density Parity-Check Stabilizer Codes.
   DM Debroy, M Li, M Newman, KR Brown
   Physical Review Letters, 121, 250502 (2018).

#### **Talks**

- o Stabilizer Slicing: Coherent Error Cancellations in Low-Density Parity-Check Stabilizer Codes. *Quantum Error Correction 2019.* July 29 – August 2, 2019. London, UK.
- o Stabilizer Slicing: Coherent Error Cancellations in Low-Density Parity-Check Stabilizer Codes. *APS March Meeting 2019.* March 4 8, 2019. Boston, MA.
- Mitigating Ion Trap Specific Error Models.
   EPiQC Monthly Seminar. April 23, 2019. Online.

#### **Posters**

- Logical Performance of 9 Qubit Compass Codes in Ion Traps with Crosstalk Errors.
   DM Debroy, M Li, S Huang, KR Brown
   IARPA LogiQ Technical Exchange Meeting. January 13 15, 2020. Washington, DC
- Logical Performance of 9 Qubit Compass Codes in Ion Traps with Crosstalk Errors.
   DM Debroy, M Li, S Huang, KR Brown
   Quantum Information Processing 2020. January 6 10, 2020. Shenzhen, CN
- Logical Performance of 9 Qubit Compass Codes in Ion Traps with Crosstalk Errors.
   DM Debroy, M Li, S Huang, KR Brown
   IARPA LogiQ Program PI Meeting. July 1 2, 2019. Boulder, CO
- Stabilizer Slicing: Coherent Error Cancellations in Low-Density Parity-Check Stabilizer Codes.
   DM Debroy, M Li, M Newman, KR Brown
   NSF Software-Tailored Architectures for Quantum codesign Poster Session. June 19, 2019. Durham, NC.

- Stabilizer Slicing: Coherent Error Cancellations in Low-Density Parity-Check Stabilizer Codes.
   DM Debroy, M Li, M Newman, KR Brown
   NSF Expeditions in Practical Scale Quantum Computing Poster Session. May 22, 2019. Chicago, IL.
- Stabilizer Slicing: Coherent Error Cancellations in Low-Density Parity-Check Stabilizer Codes.
   DM Debroy, M Li, M Newman, KR Brown
   IARPA LogiQ Program Technical Exchange Meeting. January 22 24, 2019. Dallas, TX
- Stabilizer Slicing: Coherent Error Cancellations in Low-Density Parity-Check Stabilizer Codes.
   DM Debroy, M Li, M Newman, KR Brown
   Quantum Information Processing 2019. January 14 18, 2019. Boulder, CO

# **Teaching Experience**

Recitation Instructor

**Duke University** 

O PHYS 151L: Mechanics for Engineers

Spring 2018

Taught 2-hour lectures on the material covered in class, along with helping to write quizzes and practice problems.

Also graded and held office hours.

Recitation Instructor Duke University

PHYS 152L: Electromagnetism for Engineers

Fall 2017

Taught 2-hour lectures on the material covered in class, along with helping to write quizzes and practice problems.

Also graded and held office hours.

Lab Instructor Duke University

PHYS 142L: Electromagnetism for Pre-Meds

Summer 2017

Led 2-hour lab sessions where I taught the theory behind the lab, along with helping students set up and run the labs. Also graded and held office hours. Was the primary TA for the course.

Lab Instructor Duke University

PHYS 142L: Electromagnetism for Pre-Meds

Spring 2017

Led 2-hour lab sessions where I taught the theory behind the lab, along with helping students set up and run the labs. Also graded and held office hours.

Lab Instructor Duke University

PHYS 152L: Electromagnetism for Engineers

Led 2-hour lab sessions where I taught the theory behind the lab, along with helping students set up and run the labs. Also graded and held office hours.

#### **Outreach Activities**

#### **Physics Circles Seminar Speaker**

North Carolina School of Science and Math

Seminar Speaker

Oct 2019

Physics Circles is a seminar series held at NCSSM to teach high schoolers about advanced topics in physics. My talk was the first of the series, and focused on basic quantum computing principles, an explanation of the Deutsch-Josza algorithm, and a very basic overview of quantum error correction.

#### **Quantum Error Correction Lecturer**

**UCSB School for Scientific Thought** 

Guest Speaker

The School for Scientific Thought program at UCSB is aimed at inspiring students from underrepresented minority groups to pursue degrees in STEM by offering multi-week courses on advanced topics they would not see in their schools. My lecture was a video guest lecture within a course on Quantum Computing. I received training from New York Hall of Science Explainer program on how to best convey the information effectively.

#### District Science Fair Judge

North Carolina School of Science and Math

Physics and Mathematics/Engineering Categories

2017, 2019, 2020

NCSAS Judge

North Carolina School of Science and Math

MS/HS/HS Advanced Mathematics Judge

2020